Yenwen kuo

Phone: (404) 960-5715 | Email: ywkuouxui@gmail.com | Atlanta, GA | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yenwenkuo | Portfolio: www.yenwenkuo.design.com

SUMMARY

Solutions-savvy UX/UI Designer with a unique blend of backgrounds in performing arts, scientific research, education, and hospitality. Certificate in UX/UI Design from Georgia Institute of Technology. Strengths in creativity, teamwork, and building projects from ideation to execution. Fine arts background coupled with strong interpersonal skills, analytical and research skills, and an eye for modern design principles make me a valuable addition to any team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical: HTML, CSS, GitHub, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery

UX/UI Design Tools: Atomic Design, UI Grids and Composition, Color Theory, Heuristic Evaluation, Typography, Interaction Design and Iconography, Storyboarding, Decision Flow Diagrams, User Need Identification, User Experience Interviewing, Persona Creation, Insight Synthesis, Usability Testing, Wireframe, Prototyping

Languages: English, Mandarin Chinese

Projects

The Department of Homeland Security | Government Website Redesign | URL

The aim of this project was to redesign and update the Department of Homeland Security website with a focus on the user experience in navigating the website.

- Skills: Stakeholder research and history, Persona Creation, Identifying User Path(s),
 Usability testing, Heuristic Evaluation & Redline Annotation, Data Analysis, Card Sorting,
 Sitemap, Wireframing (low to Hi), UI Design Style Guide, Interaction Design, Prototyping.
- Technologies Used: Figma, Miro, Google Drive, Zoom.

Atlanta Women for Equality | Non-Profit Organization Website Redesign | URL

Atlanta Women for Equality is a 501(c)(3) non-profit legal aid organization dedicated to helping women students assert their legal rights to equitable treatment and equal opportunities in the education system. This project aimed to redesign the website to improve the user experience, convey the mission and services of the organization, and increase donations.

- Skills: Stakeholder Interview, User Research (Interviews + Surveys), Persona Creation,
 Usability testing, Heuristic Evaluation & Redline Annotation, Data Analysis, Card Sorting,
 Sitemap, Wireframing (low to Hi), UI Design Style Guide, Interaction Design, Prototyping.
- Technologies Used: Figma, Miro, Google Drive, Zoom, Trello.

Travel Safe Mobile App | URL

The goal of this project was to create a post-pandemic mobile travel app with safety in mind, focusing on creating an account.

• Skills: User Research (Interviews + Surveys) and Analysis, Mobile User Experience Design (UX-UI), Storyboarding, Paper sketch, Wireframing, Prototyping, In-Person User Testing.

• Technologies Used: Figma, Miro, Google Drive.

EXPERIENCE

International Association of Dance Medicine and Science Promotion Committee Member (Volunteer)

January 2021 - Present **Remote**

- Creating graphic and video content for social media via Canva.
- Managing LinkedIn account and Forum, increase following up to 50%.
- Working and collaborating with international committee members (UK, USA, and Brazil).

Inspire Health March 2016 – Present

STOTT PILATES® Certified Instructor | Client Service Representative

Atlanta, GA

- Started as a Client Service Representative with great communication skills to ensure the clients were scheduled with future appointments and the daily operation ran smoothly.
- Meanwhile, was accepted into the apprentice program, completed the training, and passed the full level 1 certification program with five different apparatus.
- As a certified Pilates Instructor, providing bespoke one-on-one training programs for clients from elite athletes to rehab populations, and group lessons.

Atlanta Optimal Performance Symposium

April - September 2019

Co-Founder | Organizer | Presenter

Atlanta, GA

- Created and organized a full-day symposium on Dancers' wellness 0 -> 1.
- Designed social media content and promotion materials.
- Ticked sold and broke even for the cost of the event for the first year.

Royal Caribbean Cruiseline International

April 2006 - September 2014

Dance Captain | Wardrobe Supervisor | Dancer

International Water

- Dance Captain: maintained the integrity of the shows and provided performance notes to the cast, created cast schedule and voyager report to the head office, and handover notes to the next cast.
- Wardrobe Supervisor: laundered the costumes and repaired the damage, voyage report to the head office, and handover notes to the next cast.
- Dancer: Muster station leader for the boat drill, performed the production shows, taught social dance classes to the passengers, backstage tour, and VIP Q&A.

EDUCATION

Certificate in UX/UI Design

Georgia Institue of Technology, Atlanta

September 2022

MSc Dance Science

Trinity Laban Conservatoire of Music and Dance, London

September 2015

BFA in Dance

Shenandoah University, Winchester VA

May 2005